edweb.net 2010-06-20

# the edWeb - Privacy Policy

Privacy Policy

Last Updated: February 17, 2010

This Privacy Policy explains how the edWeb, LLC ("we" or "us") collects, protects, uses and shares information about you when you use the edWeb.

The edWeb is a professional networking website for the education community. When you register you are asked for professional information that can help us connect you with other members of the education community based on your job function, your educational interests, the kind of institution you work in, and your geographic location. Your profile on the edWeb can be viewed by any other member of the edWeb. Since this is a professional site, this will encourage greater collaboration. Do not include any information in your personal profile that you do not want to share with the entire edWeb community.

You can adjust your personal settings to limit who can contact you on the edWeb. These settings can be updated at any time by clicking on "My Settings" on your personal member page.

Your Profile Information

When you register on the edWeb, you create a personal profile that includes your full name, title, department, institution, city, state/province, zip/postal code, and country. You have the option to add a personal photo, a biography, your educational interests, and organizations you are affiliated with. This information is displayed as your profile information to all members of the edWeb.

When you join the edWeb you take a survey of your functions and interests in the educational community. This information helps us connect you with other members of the edWeb who have similar roles and interests. It also helps us place appropriate advertising and messages on the pages you view on the site. Your survey responses are not displayed publicly on the edWeb.

Your user ID (login) is your email address and you create a private password. Your email address is not displayed by the edWeb. You are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of your password and for all activities that occur under your password.

When you register for the edWeb, you can control which members of the edWeb can contact you: contacts and friends, members of your communities, members of selected segments of the education community, all members of the edWeb, or no one. You can change these settings at any time by going to the "My Settings" link on your personal home page.

Sharing Content on the edWeb

As an edWeb Member, you can share content, such as a blog, photos, and resource files you have uploaded. This information will be available to other members of the edWeb if you allow access to the information through your privacy settings. You can customize who on the edWeb is allowed access to your information.

You can also form edWeb communities to make it easier to share information and resources and collaborate with a group of your peers. If you form the community, you are the administrator and control the community settings. The administrator is responsible for determining how other members of the edWeb may access the community and to what degree the community's discussions, blog, files and other content are accessible to other members of the edWeb. A community may be public, private or hidden and the content within the community may have a variety of policies governing how other members of the site interact with it.

Although we allow you to set privacy options that limit access to the content of your personal and community pages, please be aware that no security measures are perfect or impenetrable. We also cannot control the actions of other members whom you may allow to access your profile. Therefore, we cannot and do not guarantee that your information will not be viewed by unauthorized persons.

How We Use Your Information

We will not disclose any personally identifiable information about edWeb members except as described in this Privacy Policy.

With the exceptions that we explain here, we do not give or sell individual information to advertisers. We use aggregated information to help edWeb members connect with other members who share common roles, interests, and characteristics. We also use aggregated information to help the advertisers reach the target audience they want to reach. We may also disclose aggregate information in order to describe our membership audience and services to prospective partners, advertisers, and other third parties, and for other lawful purposes.

The edWeb is created as an advertiser-supported site so we can continue to make edWeb services available for free to educators. It is our intent to provide only education-related advertisements that might be of interest to you. We may use information in your profile without identifying you individually for the purpose of placing advertisements on pages that you view. Our own servers serve all advertisements that appear on the site. The site will not provide any personally identifiable information about you to any advertiser on the site. If you click on an advertisement on the edWeb that takes you to third party page, it is your choice to provide your personal contact information.

The edWeb uses members' institution information to append additional information from public and private sources on school demographic characteristics. The purpose of this is to help edWeb members from schools with similar characteristics or in the same school district to connect with one another, and also to enable advertisers to offer more targeted products and services.

We may conduct research on our users' demographics, interests, and behavior based upon the information you provide us or in response to polls/surveys of members. This research would be compiled and analyzed on an aggregated basis. Your responses are kept anonymous.

We may disclose personally identifiable information under the following circumstances:

  * When you register for the site, if you have selected the option to receive information from edWeb partner organizations, we may provide your name, job function, email address, location, and institution contact information to our partner organizations so they can contact you directly.
  * If you respond to an invitation to join the edWeb from one of our partner organizations, we may provide your name, job function, email address, location, and institution contact information to that organization so they can contact you directly.
  * If you send e-mail from the Site, your address will appear as the return address of that e-mail.
  * If you ask us to put you on our opt-out email list, we will provide this information to our authorized service providers so you DO NOT receive additional emails from us. This is required by federal CAN-SPAM legislation.
  * If we conduct campaigns to invite other members of the education community to join the edWeb, we will provide your contact information to our authorized service providers so you DO NOT receive duplicate email invitations from us.
  * We employ subcontractors and service providers who help us develop and maintain the edWeb. They have access to our user information, so that they can perform their services for us, including maintaining our core engine, hosting services, and performing system maintenance and enhancement. These parties are subject to confidentiality agreements that restrict their use and disclosure of information they obtain through their relationship with us.
  * As required by applicable law, or in response to legal process, to protect our rights or property, or to protect our safety or the safety of our users or others.

In addition, the edWeb may use your personal information to:

  * Contact you by email or phone regarding your membership and activities on the site.
  * To assist you if you have lost your user ID or need help changing your user ID or password.

Email Communications

Email communication is an important aspect of the edWeb. When you register for the edWeb you give us your permission to use email to send you periodic updates and information and to use your email address to send you notifications of activities related to your participation on the site. You can update your permissions at any time in "My Settings" to customize the email notifications you receive. If at any time you are concerned about the volume of email you are receiving from the edWeb, please contact us at info@edweb.net.

Cookies and Other Technologies We Use

When we track activity on the edWeb, we collect information such as your IP address, browser type and version, and pages you view. We receive an IP address each time you view the Site, because our server automatically reports it to us. We may collect your connection information including details of IP addresses, operating systems, browsers, versions, and the URLs of web pages with links which you use to get to the Site (but not e-mail addresses) as part of our analysis of the site. We use this information in our business for various purposes, including diagnosing service or technology problems, assessing and maintaining system security, and/or displaying the most appropriate advertising messages. We do not track any URLs that you type into your browser that are not URLs associated with the site and we do not track you across the Internet once you leave our site. We gather this information for all edWeb members. By accessing the site, you unconditionally consent to allow us to collect your connection information and use that information in accordance with this Privacy Policy for any purpose not prohibited by applicable law.

We use "session cookies" to manage your experience on our site. A session cookie is a small piece of information we ask your browser to send to us along with each request you make to view a page on the edWeb. We use this information so that you can best take advantage of the features of the site during your visit. Your browser will no longer send session cookies to us either when you close your browser or when you log out. The next time you visit us, you will be given new session cookies. This is what differentiates session cookies from permanent cookies; permanent cookies are stored on your computer, and your browser will be able to send the same information during your visit as was sent during earlier visits. We use permanent cookies to understand more fully how members are using the edWeb and how we can improve it.

When we send you emails, we may use a variety of mechanisms including the use of embedded images to determine the number of members who open our emails. These images would also allow us to count users who have visited the edWeb and to deliver co-branded services. When you click on a link in an email, we may record this individual response to allow us to customize our offerings to you. Embedded images may also be used to conduct research on behalf of some partners on their websites for auditing purposes and/or to determine aggregate information about users, including demographic and usage information. Embedded images are not used to access your personally identifiable information, but they are a technique we may use to compile aggregated statistics about usage of the edWeb. Embedded images collect only a limited set of information including a cookie number, time and date of a page view, originating IP address, and a description of the page on which the embedded images resides. If you find our site using a search engine, the search engine and the search term used may be transmitted back to our ad-serving service providers via a cookie. This information is anonymous and does not contain your name, address, telephone number, or e-mail address. This information is used only in the aggregate to evaluate how users reach our site.

In addition, some of our advertisers use third-party networks to serve their advertisements on the edWeb. Often, these third-party advertising companies use cookies, web beacons, and similar technologies to measure advertisement effectiveness. We do not control, nor do we have access to, their cookies or the information they obtain. Use of their tracking technology is subject to their own privacy policies.

Security

We believe we take appropriate precautions to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. Certain parts of the site use a secure web server, which allows web browser programs to interact with the server via an encrypted session using a Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) connection between you and us. Users may move in and out of secured areas on the Site. You should be able to identify when you are in a secure area by "https" or a lock appearing on the screen. This will depend on the type of browser used.

Do not share your password with anyone. We will never ask you for your password. If you are using a computer to which others have access, such as one in a computer lab, Internet cafe, or public library, always remember to log out and close your browser window when leaving the site. Do not save your password on a public or shared computer.

No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. While we strive to use appropriate means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee the absolute security of any information you disclose via the edWeb, including via e-mail. When disclosing any personal information, you should remain mindful of the fact that it is potentially accessible by unauthorized persons. By disclosing any information, you accept the inherent security risks of providing information and dealing online over the Internet and will not hold us responsible for any breach of security. We disclaim all liability for the security of information transmitted through the Internet.

Inviting Colleagues to Join the edWeb

You may invite individuals who are qualified members of the education community to become a member of the edWeb and to become a linked "Contact & Friend" of yours. If you are the administrator of an edWeb community, you may invite individuals to join your community and be added as a linked "Contact & Friend." If you choose to use our invitation service for personal or community purposes, we will ask you to enter your colleague's email address. We will automatically send an email inviting that individual to join the edWeb. We store the email address used to send this invitation so that we can verify that the recipient has a valid invitation to join the edWeb and also to register a linked connection between you, your community, if applicable, and your contact or friend. We may periodically send reminders to individuals who do not reply. We do not use this information for any other purposes.

Links to Third Parties

The edWeb may contain links to third-party websites not operated by us. If you follow links from the edWeb to other websites, those sites have their own privacy and data collection practices. This Privacy Policy only applies to the edWeb and the information we collect. We do not monitor other websites nor do we have any control or responsibility for them, their content or their privacy policies.

International Use

If you are using the edWeb from outside the United States, you consent to the transfer of your information to the United States for processing and maintaining in accordance with this Privacy Policy and our User Agreement. You consent to the application of United States law in all matters concerning this site.

Changes to our Privacy Policy

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. You should consult this Privacy Policy periodically to learn of such changes. The most recent version of the Privacy Policy will always be posted on the edWeb, with the "Effective Date" posted at the top of the Policy. We will inform you of any material change to this Privacy Policy that affects the way we handle your personally identifiable information by posting a notice on the site.

Contacting the edWeb

You may contact the edWeb by phone at 800-575-6015 or by email at . Our mailing address is PO Box 1387, Princeton, NJ 08542.
